阿尔卡拉斯/门西克 6-4 6-4 布勃利克/弗里茨 · 赛后场上采访
Jakub, Carlos, an entertaining match.
门西克 卡洛斯 这场球很好看
Jakub, I want to start with you.
门西克 先从你开始
No one here plays a ton of doubles.
这里没人经常打双打
What is the last three
过去三四天
or four days look like for you guys as far
你们的双打训练
as doubles practice goes?
是什么样的？
We didn't give it that much to be honest
说实话这一周没怎么练
during the week.
这一周
But no, especially me sometimes
不过 尤其是我 一年里
during the year I play few doubles.
很少打双打
I mean Carlos, it doesn't matter
我是说 卡洛斯不管
if he plays singles or doubles.
打单打还是双打都一样
I mean, I think he could be world
我觉得他就算打双打
number one even in doubles,
也能拿世界第一
but no, I mean, I'm happy.
不过 我很开心
Great effort obviously.
显然大家都拼了
So, yeah, especially for me
所以 尤其是对我来说
after the tough loss in the singles
单打输得那么难受之后
that I was able to come back
还能扳回来
and bring the points
把这1分
to the lockers.
带回更衣室
Carlos, everyone in here can see it.
卡洛斯 这里每个人都看得到
You've got a big smile on your face almost
你几乎每一分之后
after every point.
脸上都挂着大大的笑
Are you having as much fun out here
你在场上真有
as it appears?
看起来那么开心吗？
Well, I don't know.
嗯 我也不知道
I'm just trying to have fun, you know,
我就是想玩得开心
every place that I go
不管去哪儿
and every court that I played on.
在哪块场地上打球
So, and especially playing doubles.
尤其是打双打
I love playing doubles.
我喜欢打双打
I'm not used
我不太习惯
to, I don't usually play doubles, you know,
我平时不怎么打双打
the question before you know,
就像刚才那个问题
probably my last doubles was here
我上一次打双打可能就是
in the Laver Cup last year.
去年在拉沃尔杯
So you can imagine, you know,
所以你可以想象
so I just try to enjoy trying
我就是想享受 同时
to be better, you know, on the things.
在一些事情上做得更好
I'm trying to use the doubles, you know,
我想借双打
on trying to improve my, you know,
去提高
my tennis, my things,
我的网球 我的一些东西
a couple of adjustments.
做一些调整
So I'm just trying to enjoy as much
所以我就是想尽量
as I can and obviously, you know,
享受 当然
having a partner, you know,
有一个像门西克
like Jakub, it's really easy to have fun
这样的搭档 在场上
on the court.
很容易就能开心起来
We
我们
we know what you've accomplished
都知道你在单打场上
on the singles court.
拿到过什么
I guess my question
我想问的是
is, and Jakub just said it, how are you
门西克刚也说了 你怎么
so good at doubles, too?
连双打也打这么好？
Well, I used to play a lot of doubles
嗯 我以前
when I was when I was
小时候
when I was young.
打过很多双打
Well, when I was younger, let's say.
好吧 年纪更小的时候吧
But I don't know.
但我也说不清
I just feel it, you know, on singles.
我在单打里也有这种感觉
I'm trying to go to the net as much
我尽量多上网
as I can.
能上就上
I practice the ball in every practice a lot.
每次训练我都练很多
Obviously the movement
当然 双打的跑位
and the spaces
和空间
of the doubles, sometimes I get
有时候我会
a little bit lost but you know
有点迷失 不过
in general I'm trying to be better
总的来说我每一局
after every game, which
都想打得更好
which I really appreciate
这一点我很珍惜
and I'm really happy that I just I was able
我很高兴在比赛最后
to play really great tennis
能打出
at the end of the match
非常好的网球
but I, you know, it comes natural.
不过 这是很自然的事
I want to bring the vice captain Mr.
我想请副队长
Tim Henman over.
亨曼先生过来
Tim, go back 10 days or so ago.
蒂姆 回到10天前左右
Did you know this was going to be a duo
你知道会是这对组合
that was going to play here
在这里出战吗？
or do they have to prove it to you
还是他们得向你
and Yannick over the last four days
和诺阿证明自己 在过去四天
in practice?
的训练里？
You say 10 minutes ago or
你说的是10分钟前
10 days ago?
还是10天前？
Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry. Sorry. 10 days ago.
抱歉 抱歉 10天前
They play very well in San Francisco.
他们在旧金山打得很好
So we didn't really have a whole lot
所以我们其实没多少时间
of time to practice doubles,
练双打
but these two have a great chemistry both
但他俩在场上场下
on and off the court.
都很有默契
So we felt pretty confident
所以我们很有信心
that they could come out and do the job.
他们能上场把活干好
That's exactly what they did.
他们也正是这么做的
Difficult matchup against Fritz
对上弗里茨和布勃利克
and Bublik.
不好打
But they played the big points
但他们关键分
so well and once they got
打得太好了 一拿下
the first set I think they were went
第一盘 他们
from strength to strength.
就越打越强
And finally,
最后
you guys are only up two points,
你们只领先2分
but you won three
但今天四场
of the four matches today.
你们赢了三场
More than anything,
最重要的是
do you feel like you're going home tonight
你觉得今晚回去
with a ton of momentum?
带着满满的势头吗？
Yeah, I mean, it's the first day
是的 这是第一天
as we know.
大家都知道
Tomorrow is double points
明天是双倍积分
if you like.
可以这么说
And but I think on reflection,
但回头看
the day session,
日场那两场
they were two tight matches.
都很胶着
We could have won them both
我们可能两场都赢
or lost them both.
也可能两场都输
But the way we play this evening,
但今晚这么打
I think it does give us momentum,
我觉得确实给了我们势头
but there's still a long way to go.
不过路还很长
There's a lot of tennis on Saturday
周六周日
and Sunday, but we're going to be ready.
还有很多比赛 但我们会准备好
Guys, congratulations.
两位 恭喜